Bhautik Pethani

437-986-6382 | <u>bhautikpethani42@gmail.com</u> | Toronto, ON linkedin.com/in/bhautikpethani/ | bhautikpethani.github.io/BhautikPethaniPortfolio/

SUMMARY

Mobile Application Developer with 2 years of industrial experience with knowledge of the complete lifecycle of Software Development. I am currently pursuing a Mobile Application Design and Development course and actively looking for a co-op opportunity.

SKILLS

- Proficient in mobile application development using iOS (Swift and SwiftUI), Android (Java and Kotlin), Flutter and React-Native
- Expertise in Web Development with JavaScript, React-TypeScript, PHP (Core and Laravel), .NET, Bootstrap,
 HTML5 and CSS
- Experience with object-oriented programming languages such as C, C++, Java and C#
- Worked with SQL, SQLite, SQLite Room Database and XML
- Experience in Agile/Scrum software development methodology
- Hands-on experience with IDEs such as XCode, Android Studio, IntelliJ, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Atom, git bash and other development platforms
- Experienced in using Git and Bitbucket for version control and Jira, Trello, and Asana for Task tracking

EDUCATION

Mobile Application Design and Development

Jan 2022 - Present

Lambton College, Toronto, Ontario

(Courses: Android and iOS development fundamentals, Swift and Java programming, Mobile browser application development, Mobile Frontend and Backend development, Software Quality Assurance Testing)

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Jun 2017 – Sep 2020

Uka Tarsadiya University, Gujarat, India

(Courses: Algorithm and Data structures, Database management system, Web development, Software development, Software Engineering)

EXPERIENCE

Junior Application Developer

(Contract) Jan 2022 - Nov 2022

Webmount Studios, Montreal, Canada (Remote)

- Designed software architecture and developed multiple iOS mobile applications using Swift and Objective-C
- Developed backend using firebase-lambda, Firestore and Firebase-Cloud-Messaging
- Worked with AlamoFire to implement user authentication, login and store user-specific account and transaction data
- Worked with RxSwift library for composing asynchronous and event-based code
- Monitored and maintained application workflow and infrastructure using Datadog
- Debugged and fixed potential bugs, thus improving app performance by 12%

Mobile Application Developer (Cross-Platform)

Oct 2020 - Oct 2021

Planics Dev, Gujarat, India

Experienced with UI design and interaction in **Flutter (Dart)** with the backend using data binding methods and **third-party libraries** like **Google Maps** and **Maps** APIs

- Worked with cloud services such as Firebase and AWS for database and social media authentication
- Troubleshoot and analyze problem reports
- Identifying potential problems and resolving application bottlenecks

FREELANCING PROJECTS

HireOpp – Android and iOS

HireOpp is a real-time location-based application that helps users connect and interact with all nearby vendors, freelancers, professional service providers, businesses, etc.

- Developed the app using Flutter and Dart
- Implemented RestAPIs, third-party libraries, Firestore, Firebase Auth (Social Media Authentication) and Google Map APIs
- Used the Providers and Cached Network Image functionality, improving the application's performance by 15%

Patient Connect – Android and iOS

Patient Connect is developed to provide authentic information with their own Doctors being the source. The information can be simply FAQs on a particular disease or DO's and DON'Ts, Myth Busters, animated and personalized educational videos, Exercises and much more.

- Developed the app using Flutter and Dart
- Implemented RestAPIs, third-party libraries, Media Bucket and Space Allocation for the media on the server
- Worked with **File IO Operations** by connecting RestAPIs

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

FitME – iOS (XCode)

FitMe is a fitness and health-based app that suggests various exercises to users based on their lifestyle to achieve their body goals.

- Developed the app using Swift, SwiftUI and Storyboard
- Implemented freemium model, thus developed In-app purchases as per Apple's guidelines
- Implemented Media Downloading and displaying from AWS S3 using the SwiftyJSON
- Worked with **Figma** to develop UI/UX designs for the application

Task Manager - Android (Android Studio)

Task Manager is developed to manage our daily tasks in a categorized manner with images and audio recordings.

- Developed the app using Android, Java and XML
- Implemented Media Recorder to record user messages from a microphone
- Used Room DAOs library for data persistence and interaction with the database (SQLite)
- Worked with the file read and write to upload images locally